<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>TensorTunes</title>
    <link>http://localhost:36047/</link>
    <description>Recent content on TensorTunes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.129.0</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:36047/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Deconding From Language Models</title>
      <link>http://localhost:36047/posts/decoding-from-language-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:36047/posts/decoding-from-language-models/</guid>
      <description>A quick refresher on Autoregressive text generation Autoregressive language models generate text through a sequential process of predicting one token at a time. The model takes a sequence of tokens $ \lbrace y \rbrace _{&amp;lt;t} $ as input and outputs a new token $ \hat{y_t} $. This process repeats iteratively, with each newly generated token becoming part of the input for the subsequent prediction.
At each time step $ t $, the model computes a vector of scores $ \mathbf{S} \in \mathbb{R}^V $, where $ V $ is the size of the vocabulary.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Retrieval to RAG (Part - 1)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:36047/posts/from-retrieval-to-rag-part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:36047/posts/from-retrieval-to-rag-part1/</guid>
      <description>stuff</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantization of Language Models</title>
      <link>http://localhost:36047/posts/quantization/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:36047/posts/quantization/</guid>
      <description>The Return of the Intro So you are a AI enthuasist, and want to run llms locally on your local on or you are a multi-billion dollar start up and you want to serve your prestine new model to you coustomers, either way you should know about qunatization
Now Qunatization can be Broadly classified into 2 types
QAT (Quantization Aware Training) PTQ (Post Training Qunatization) Another way you can Look into Qunatiztion is weather if you have a Finetuned model (ie, a model thay you are trying just to serve) or a model you are trying to FInetune on your own dataset, For finetunig a Instructino tuned (SFT) model, you can your use techniques like adapters or Just do QLoRA, which is the most popular and the most effective right now.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
